Jason Bens

390 La Strada Drive, San Jose, CA Jason.L.Bens@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/jasonbens github.com/JasonBens

Biography

I am a hardware engineer who loves the fast pace and constant change of product design. I like learning new technologies and applying them in novel ways. I have experience in all stages of the product design pipeline, including hardware design, design validation, regulatory/safety compliance including EMC, and contract manufacturer management.

Skill Summary

| \sim | | • |
|--------|-------|------|
| Com | peten | CIES |
| | | CICL |

Schematic Capture PCB Design/Layout Analog/Digital Design Electromagnetic Compliance System Integration Circuit Simulation Prototyping and Test Signal Integrity Validation High Speed Design High Density Design Root Cause Analysis Contract Manuf. Management

Tools

Allegro/OrCAD Altium LTSpice/NgSpice NI LabView MATLAB ARM Assembly Python

Experience

Electrical Engineer Pensar Development

Seattle, Washington August 2015 - September 2018

- Designed several USB 2.0 and USB 3.0 hub boards for a medical ultrasound device with emphasis on specialized galvanic isolation for patient safety.
- Spearheaded the EMC effort to reduce the device's RF emissions from 30 dB above the IEC-60601-1 limit to 15 dB below the limit using both electrical and mechanical modifications.
- Working with the firmware team, instrumented the USB hub board and created an automated manufacturing test suite for it in NI LabView.
- Coordinated with local fabrication labs and larger contract manufacturers to prototype the device and bring it into production.
- Performed signal integrity measurements on high speed lines (DDR, USB 3.0, low MHz sine wave) and designed mitigations to reduce the effects of nearby RF coupling.

Electrical Engineer Electroimpact

Mukilteo, Washington September 2014 - August 2015

- Designed a sensor system to monitor the safety brakes on a carbon fiber placement gantry used in construction of the Boeing 747.
- Integrated a positional control system with sensors for realtime control of a mobile gantry for carbon fiber placement.
- Supervised the installation of automated assembly jigs for aircraft wing assembly lines.
- Designed 24V, 120V, 208V, and 480V AC and DC power distribution systems.

Keihanna Science City, Kyoto, Japan Advanced Telecommunications Research Institute International July 2012 - August 2013

- Applied stacked denoising autoencoders to generate hypothetical functional MRI (fMRI) activations.
- Developed stimulus routines to collect data on behavioural tasks from human test subjects.
- Analyzed fMRI, MEG, EEG, and anatomical MRI data to locate and visualize neural activations measured during experiments.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical Engineering GPA: 7.58/9.00

University of Victoria Graduated 2014

• Specializations in Computational Intelligence and Electromagnetics & Photonics

Diploma in Electronics Engineering Technology GPA: 3.82/4.00 with Honours

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology Graduated 2011

Jason Bens 1/1